Arise for Social Justice Records, 1956-2010 (bulk 1985-2010)
Sophia Smith Collection
- SERIES IX. HEALTH CARE
  - Arise Health Care Access Campaign (aka Health Insurance Access Campaign)
    - General 1993-94, undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Coalition
      - Research 1993 (Box 10, Folder 2)
      - Fair Care Coalition/Cuidado de Salud para Todas
        - General 1993-94, undated (Box 10, Folder 3-4)
        - Press conference 23 Sep 1993 (Box 10, Folder 5)
        - Meeting packet 13 Oct 1993 (Box 10, Folder 6)
        - Protest at Senator Kennedy hearing 25 Oct 1993 (Box 10, Folder 7)
        - Stark/Wellstone bill Nov 1993 (Box 10, Folder 8)
      - Franklin/Hampshire Health Care Coalition (F/HHCC) 1993-96, undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
      - Single Payer Across the Nation (SPAN) 1994, undated (Box 10, Folder 10)
      - State-wide Campaign for a Single Payer Health Care Referendum 1993-95 (Box 10, Folder 11)
      - Universal Health Care Action Network (UHCAN)
        - General 1993-98, undated (Box 10, Folder 12-13)
        - Conference, "Universal Health Care: Setting a Course for '95 and Beyond" Oct 1994 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Grant funding 1995-97 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Reports to Arise Board 1993-94 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Notes for presentation undated (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Insurance research
      - General 1993 (Box 10, Folder 18)
      - Health Maintenance Organizations (HMO) 1993 (Box 10, Folder 19)
      - Insurance companies 1992-93, undated (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Small business advertising campaign circa 1994 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Single payer public policy ballot referendum
      - General 1993-94 (Box 10, Folder 22)
      - Petitioning 1994 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Clippings 1985-98, undated (Box 10, Folder 24-26)
  - Conferences and summits
    - Family Health Summit: Infant Survival, Western New England College 4 Jun 1993 (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - "The Fight for Abortion Rights and Reproductive Freedom," Hampshire College 1993-94, 1997-98 (Box 10, Folder 28-29)
  - Legislation (proposed)
    - National, miscellaneous 1990-94, undated (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - American Health Security Act of 1993 (Box 10, Folder 31)
    - Clinton Health Care Plan 1993-94 (Box 10, Folder 32-33)
    - Wellstone bill (S491) 1993-94 (Box 10, Folder 34)
    - Massachusetts 1987-2005, undated (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - Organizations and programs
    - Miscellaneous circa 1988-2000, undated (Box 10, Folder 36)
    - Alliance for the Mentally Ill (AMI) of Western Massachusetts 1986-88 (Box 10, Folder 37)
    - American Public Health Association (APHA) 1993, undated (Box 10, Folder 38)
    - Baystate Medical Center: Conversations in Community Health 1993-96, undated (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - Commonhealth 1992-93, undated (Box 10, Folder 40)
    - Families USA: Health Reform Action Party kit Oct 1993 (Box 10, Folder 41)
    - Gray Panthers 1987-95, undated (Box 10, Folder 42)
    - Health Action Committee circa 1994 (Box 10, Folder 43)
    - Health Care for All
      - General 1986-96, undated (Box 10, Folder 44-46)
      - Conference: Health Care Organizing in the New Millennium May 1995 (Box 10, Folder 47)
    - Hemlock Society: Hemlock Quarterly 1992 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Interreligious Health Care Access Campaign 1993, undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Massachusetts Fair Share 1986, undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Massachusetts Healthy Start Coalition 1990-92, undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Massachusetts Law Reform Institute, Basic Benefits Training re: health care 1993 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Medicaid
      - General 1984-98, undated (Box 11, Folder 6-12)
      - Basic Benefits Training, MLRI 30 Nov 1993 (Box 11, Folder 13)
      - Masshealth: managed care 1992-2001, undated (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Medicare 1985-92, undated (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Northeast Ohio Coalition for National Health Care 1993-95 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Physicians for a National Health Program (PNHP) 1989-96, undated (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Springfield Department of Health and Human Services 1989-97 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Springfield Southwest Community Health Center 1997, undated (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Western Massachusetts Working Group for National Health Care 1990 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Subjects
    - Alternative medicine 1992-93, undated (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Children 1987-98, undated (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Disabled 1988-93 (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Free and low-cost care 1988, undated (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - Homeless 1993-94 (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - Reproductive health/rights 1992-95 (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - Seniors 1989-93, undated (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - Single-payer
      - General 1992-95, undated (Box 11, Folder 28)
      - Fact sheets 1992-94, undated (Box 11, Folder 29)
    - Unemployed 1991-96, undated (Box 11, Folder 30)
    - Women 1993-98, undated (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - Reference files
    - General 1989-99, undated (Box 11, Folder 32-35)
    - Medical industry PAC contributions to members of congress 1993 (Box 11, Folder 36)
- SERIES X. HIV/AIDS PREVENTION AND EDUCATION
  - Arise
    - General 1992-98, undated (Box 11, Folder 37)
    - Clippings 1992-93, undated (Box 11, Folder 38)
    - Needle exchange
      - Advocacy 1997-2004, undated (Box 11, Folder 39)
      - Funding proposals 2002, undated (Box 11, Folder 40)
      - Reference files 1995-98 (Box 11, Folder 41)
      - Reports for Massachusetts Program 1995-97 (Box 11, Folder 42-43)
    - Sex Worker Outreach Team/Project (SWOT)
      - General 1998-2003, undated (Box 11, Folder 44)
      - Committee 1997-99, undated (Box 11, Folder 45)
      - National prostitution legislation (Box 12, Folder 1)
      - Reference files 1993-2002, undated (Box 12, Folder 2-3)
    - Women in Support of Each Other (WISE)
      - General 1998-2002, undated (Box 12, Folder 4)
      - Committee 1999-2005, undated (Box 12, Folder 5-8)
      - Group/popular education 1998-2000, undated (Box 12, Folder 9)
      - Staff 1999-2000, undated (Box 12, Folder 10)
      - Street outreach 1996-99, undated (Box 12, Folder 11)
      - Women's Group 2000-02, undated (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Arizine
      - 1998-2003 (Box 12, Folder 13-17)
      - Miscellaneous undated pages (Box 12, Folder 18)
      - Graphics undated (Box 12, Folder 19)
      - Manuscripts 1996, undated (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Arise HIV/AIDS Education and Prevention Program, Massachusetts Department of Public Health HIV/AIDS Bureau contract
      - General 1993-2002, undated (Box 12, Folder 21)
      - Women at Risk/Sex Worker Outreach Program Development meetings 1998-2001 (Box 12, Folder 22)
      - Financial
        - Budgets 1997-2001, undated (Box 12, Folder 23)
        - Order forms 2000-01, undated (Box 12, Folder 24)
        - Reports undated (Box 12, Folder 25)
      - Collaborating organizations
        - Colectiva de Proyectos de Educación Popular del VIH (CPEP) 1997 (Box 12, Folder 26)
        - Springfield Southwest Community Health Center (SSCHC) 1997-2003, undated (Box 12, Folder 27)
      - Proposal 1997-99, undated (Box 12, Folder 28)
      - Work plans 1997-2000, undated (Box 12, Folder 29)
      - Work plans response 1998-2001, undated (Box 12, Folder 30)
      - Correspondence and site visits 1998-2000, undated (Box 12, Folder 31)
      - Reports
        - Quarterly reports 1997-2000, undated (Box 12, Folder 32-36)
        - Contract Monitoring and Assessment Reports (CMAR) 1998-2002, undated (Box 12, Folder 37-39)
        - Monthly Data Reports 2001 (Box 12, Folder 40)
        - Service Delivery Reports 1998-2001 (Box 12, Folder 41)
  - Conferences and workshops
    - General 1993-98, undated (Box 12, Folder 42)
    - "Women and AIDS: Advanced Certification Training," (Marsha Burnett was a presenter), Massachusetts AIDS Training Institute 1994 (Box 12, Folder 43)
    - "Replicating Effective Programs," Common Visions Conference 30 Oct 2001 (Box 12, Folder 44)
  - Organizations
    - Miscellaneous (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - ACT UP [AIDS Coalition to Unleash Power] undated (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - AIDS Action Committee of Massachusetts 1988-98, undated (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - AIDS Allies, Inc., Springfield 1992, undated (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - ALTO AIDS [Alliance of Latinos to Overcome AIDS] 1993-94, undated (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - National Association of People with AIDS 1992-94, undated (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Positive Directions, Boston 1992-93, undated (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Springfield HIV Consortia 1993-94, undated (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Western Massachusetts Women and AIDS Work Group/Network 1992-95, undated (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Reference files
    - General 1988-2003, undated (Box 13, Folder 10-11)
    - Western Massachusetts 1990-2000, undated (Box 13, Folder 12-13)
    - Massachusetts and New England 1987-2001, undated (Box 13, Folder 14-15)
    - People of color 1992-2000, undated (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Prevention and education 1991-2000, undated (Box 13, Folder 17-18)
    - Safe sex/condoms 1986-93, undated (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Treatment 1986-2001, undated (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Women 1988-94, undated (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Newsletters
      - Miscellaneous 1992-93 (Box 13, Folder 22)
      - Allies Today, Springfield 1991-92 (Box 13, Folder 23)
      - The Body Positive 1989, 1992-94 (Box 13, Folder 24-25)
      - The Common Factor 1992-93 (Box 13, Folder 26)
      - Positively Aware 1992-94 (Box 13, Folder 27)
      - The Project News, Massachusetts north shore 1993-95 (Box 13, Folder 28)
      - PWA[C] Newsline,1992-94 (Box 13, Folder 29-31)
      - Wellspring 1990-93, undated (Box 13, Folder 32)
- SERIES XI. HOMELESSNESS, [see also SERIES IX. HEALTH CARE, SERIES XII. HOUSING, SERIES XVIII. POVERTY/ECONOMIC JUSTCE, AND SERIES XXIV. WELFARE]
  - Arise
    - General 1986-2005, undated (Box 13, Folder 33)
    - Arise/ Massachusetts Department of Public Welfare dialogue 1989-92 (Box 13, Folder 34)
    - Homeless Action Center 1987-88, undated, [see also Self-Reliance Center in SERIES XVI. PEER SUPPORT, and Restricted materials] (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Homeless Committee
      - General undated (Box 14, Folder 2)
      - Meetings and correspondence 1992 (Box 14, Folder 3-4)
    - Homeless Committee and Homeless Support Group 1993 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Homeless Employment Leadership Project (HELP) undated (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Homeless to Homes Project 1987 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Housing and Homelessness Task Force 2003 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Marsha's Apartment 2004, undated (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Sanctuary City
      - General 2004-06, undated (Box 14, Folder 10-11)
      - Emergency Shelter meetings 2004 (Box 14, Folder 12)
      - Homeless Openly United to Shelter Everyone (HOUSE) 2004, undated (Box 14, Folder 13)
      - HOUSE Gazette newsletter 2002, 2004 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Summit Motor Inn organizing and Hot Meals 1987-89, undated (Box 14, Folder 15-16)
    - Vigil to End Homelessness 31 Dec 1987 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Welfare/AFDC and homelessness
      - General undated (Box 14, Folder 18)
      - Emergency Assistance (EA) Program (includes Section 8 and 707 housing vouchers) 1987-94, undated (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Springfield and Pioneer Valley
    - General
      - Clippings, fact sheets, correspondence, and reports 1984-2003, undated (Box 14, Folder 20-21)
      - Census 1989-91, undated (Box 14, Folder 22)
      - Homelessness needs assessment notes circa 1986 (Box 14, Folder 23)
      - "Policy on Homelessness in Springfield" by Peter Friedland undated (Box 14, Folder 24)
      - "Springfield's Homeless Families" by Cheryl Pikora 1991 (Box 14, Folder 25)
    - Organizations/committees
      - Community 2000 Task Force on Homelessness 1988-89 (Box 14, Folder 26)
      - Fund for the Hungry and Homeless of Greater Springfield
        - General 1987-93, undated (Box 14, Folder 27)
        - Walk for the Hungry and Homeless 1988-94 (Box 14, Folder 28)
      - Greater Springfield Committee on Homelessness
        - General 1989 (Box 14, Folder 29)
      - Greater Springfield Homeless Coalition
        - Notes and reference materials undated (Box 14, Folder 30)
        - General 1987-90, undated (Box 14, Folder 31-32)
        - Service Providers' meetings 1986-87, 2003 (Box 14, Folder 33)
      - Homeless Information Exchange Network 1988 (Box 14, Folder 34)
      - Human Rights Committee for the Homeless of Greater Springfield 1987, undated (Box 14, Folder 35)
      - Mayor's Blue Ribbon Committee for Adequate Sheltering 1989 (Box 14, Folder 36)
      - Sheltering the Homeless in Springfield 1989-90 (Box 14, Folder 37)
      - Service Providers, Inc.
        - General 1985-87, undated (Box 14, Folder 38)
        - Board meetings 1985-88, undated (Box 14, Folder 39-40)
      - Springfield Living Center 1993 (Box 14, Folder 41)
    - Shelters
      - General 1984-93, undated (Box 14, Folder 42)
      - Armory Street 1986, undated (Box 14, Folder 43)
      - Goodwill Building, 718 State St. (proposed) 1986 (Box 14, Folder 44)
      - Horizons 1988, undated (Box 14, Folder 45)
      - Open Pantry, [see also Restricted materials]
        - General 1987-93, undated (Box 14, Folder 46)
        - Warming Place 2006, undated (Box 14, Folder 47)
      - Rotating/Overflow Shelter 1990-2003, undated (Box 14, Folder 48)
      - Springfield Redevelopment Authority Open Bed Shelter 1992, undated (Box 14, Folder 49)
      - Unified Shelter (proposed) 1988 (Box 14, Folder 50)
      - Worthington Street 1989-92, undated (Box 14, Folder 51)
  - Massachusetts
    - General
      - Clippings, fact sheets, press releases, and correspondence 1986-2003, undated (Box 14, Folder 52-53)
      - "Homelessness: Critical Issues for Policy and Practice," The Boston Foundation 1987 (Box 14, Folder 54)
      - Homeless Empowerment Program, Spare Change News sales 1993-94 (Box 14, Folder 55)
      - Metro West 1990-93, undated (Box 14, Folder 56)
      - Northern Berkshire Homeless Program 1988-89, undated (Box 14, Folder 57)
      - Results of a Study to Investigate Perceptions and Attitudes Regarding Homelessness in Massachusetts Jun 1990 (Box 14, Folder 58)
      - Shelters 1990-95, undated (Box 14, Folder 59)
      - Weld Administration Briefing Packet on Homelessness 1991 (Box 14, Folder 60)
    - Organizations/committees
      - Homeless Advocacy Task Force of Western Massachusetts 1992-94 (Box 15, Folder 1-3)
      - Massachusetts Coalition for the Homeless, [see also SERIES XXIV. WELFARE]
        - General 1986-2006, undated (Box 15, Folder 4-11)
        - Shelter Access Summit Feb 1991 (Box 15, Folder 12)
        - Streetlife/StreetSmarts newsletter 1987-2000 (Box 15, Folder 13)
      - Massachusetts Right to Housing Project 1986 (Box 15, Folder 14)
      - Masschusetts Shelter Providers Association
        - General 1990 (Box 15, Folder 15)
        - Community meetings 1993 (Box 15, Folder 16-18)
  - National
    - General 1983-95, undated (Box 15, Folder 19-21)
    - Clippings 1984-95, undated (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - Empty the Shelters (ETS) [student arm of the Kensington Welfare Rights Union] 1994, undated (Box 15, Folder 23)
    - National Coalition for the Homeless
      - General 1987-98, undated (Box 15, Folder 24)
      - Conference "America's Homeless: Strategies for '88" 11 Sep 1987 (Box 15, Folder 25)
      - Safety Network newsletter 1987-98 (Box 15, Folder 26)
    - Oakland, California, homeless services 1990-93, undated (Box 15, Folder 27)
    - U.S. House of Representatives hearing, "Homelessness in America" 23 Apr 1993 (Box 15, Folder 28)
  - Reference files
    - Homeless veterans 1989-90, undated (Box 15, Folder 29)
    - Homeless voters 1991-93 (Box 15, Folder 30)
- SERIES XII. HOUSING, [see also SERIES II. FINANCIAL MATERIALS, SERIES XI. HOMELESSNESS, and SERIES XVIII. POVERTY/ECONOMIC JUSTICE]
  - Arise for Social Justice activities 1987-2003, undated, [see also below] (Box 15, Folder 31)
  - Housing, general 1990-93, undated (Box 15, Folder 32)
  - Affordable housing 1983-98, undated (Box 15, Folder 33-36)
  - Affordable Housing Alliance
    - 1986-90 (Box 15, Folder 37-43)
    - 1991-94, undated (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - "At-Risk"/Expiring Use Subsidized Housing
    - General 1988-91, undated (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Ad-hoc Massachusetts At-Risk Housing Network 1990-91 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Springfield and region 1989-91, undated (Box 16, Folder 4-5)
  - Condominium conversion 1983-91, undated (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Habitat for Humanity undated (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Habitat International Coalition, Women and Shelter Network 1989 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Holyoke/Chicopee/Springfield Housing Coalition 1988, undated (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Holyoke Housing Group 1988-91, undated (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Housing and Land Bank Bill 1987-88 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Housing Now! Campaign 1988-91 (Box 16, Folder 12-17)
  - Housing Opportunities in Massachusetts for Everyone (HOME) Coalition
    - General 1990-94, undated (Box 16, Folder 18-21)
    - Workshop: Building Your Network circa 1990 (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - Justice Demands Housing 1989, undated (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - Low-Income Housing Information Service and Anti-Displacement Project (Box 16, Folder 24)
  - Massachusetts, Commonwealth of
    - General 1985-91, undated (Box 16, Folder 25)
    - Affordable Housing Act 1988 (Box 16, Folder 26)
    - Department of Community Affairs 1976-78 (Box 16, Folder 27)
    - Executive Office of Communities and Development
      - 1976-86 (Box 16, Folder 28-30)
      - 1987-88, undated (Box 16, Folder 31)
    - Housing Court
      - General 1986-91, undated (Box 16, Folder 32-33)
      - Landlord Stephen Gray 1988 (Box 16, Folder 34)
    - Massachusetts Housing Finance Agency 1986-88, undated (Box 16, Folder 35)
    - Massachusetts Housing Partnership 1985-93, undated (Box 16, Folder 36-37)
  - Massachusetts Housing Network, newsletter of Massachusetts Human Services Coalition 1985 (Box 16, Folder 38)
  - Massachusetts Law Reform Institute
    - Housing Advocates 1986-91 (Box 16, Folder 39)
    - Housing Information Memo 1988-94 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Massachusetts Right to Housing Project 1986-87, undated (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - National Low-Income Housing Coalition 1986-2003 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - National Association of Housing and Redevelopment Officials 1987-88 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - October 6th Coalition,1987 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - People's Conference on Affordable Housing
    - First 1986 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Second 1987 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Third 1988 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Fourth 1990 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Public housing
    - General 1987-98, undated (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Council of Large Public Housing Authorities 1987-88 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Massachusetts 1986-92, undated (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Massachusetts Union of Public Housing Tenants
      - General 1980-91, undated (Box 17, Folder 13-15)
      - "Handbook for Public Housing Grievance Procedures" undated (Box 17, Folder 16)
      - "Starting a Tenant Organization: Training Materials for Community Organizations" undated (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - Springfield Housing Authority 1983-90, undated (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development
      - General 1972-94, undated (Box 17, Folder 19)
      - Public Housing Comprehensive Improvement Assistance Program Handbook Dec 1983 (Box 17, Folder 20)
      - Lease and grievance rules 1988, undated (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - Rent control
    - Rent Control Task Force/Tenant Electoral Organizing Initiative (TEOI) 1990, undated (Box 17, Folder 22)
    - Springfield Rent Control Initiative Campaign
      - General 1988-89 (Box 17, Folder 23)
      - Clippings 1988-89, undated (Box 17, Folder 24)
      - Correspondence 1988-89, undated (Box 17, Folder 25)
      - Endorsements undated (Box 17, Folder 26)
      - Fact sheets 1988, undated (Box 17, Folder 27)
      - Fliers 1989, undated (Box 17, Folder 28)
      - Meetings 1988-89, undated (Box 17, Folder 29)
      - Petition process 1989 (Box 17, Folder 30)
      - Petition photocopies 1989 (Box 17, Folder 31)
      - Phone banks 1989 (Box 17, Folder 32)
      - Legal/research files
        - General 1981-89, undated (Box 17, Folder 33-39)
        - "An Act Enabling the City of Springfield to Control Residential Rents," 1989 (Box 17, Folder 40)
        - "Summary of Proposed Rent and Eviction Control Law" circa 1989 (Box 17, Folder 41)
        - Landlords 1989, undated (Box 17, Folder 42)
        - Springfield research studies 1989, undated (Box 17, Folder 43)
  - Single Room Occupancy Residences (SRO)
    - General
      - Reports, brochures, clippings 1979-91, undated (Box 18, Folder 1)
      - Models
        - California 1984-86 (Box 18, Folder 2)
        - Denver, Colorado undated (Box 18, Folder 3)
        - New York 1979-86, undated (Box 18, Folder 4)
        - Oregon
          - General 1980-86 (Box 18, Folder 5)
          - SRO Housing Management Handbook, Burnside Consortium, Portland, Oregon 1983 (Box 18, Folder 6)
        - Seattle, Washington 1985, undated (Box 18, Folder 7)
      - Reports and research papers
        - "Elderly and Transients in SRO Dwellings" undated (Box 18, Folder 8)
        - "Single Room Occupancy Hotels: Standing in the Way of the Gentry," Coalition for the Homeless 1985 (Box 18, Folder 9)
        - "The Single State: Shelters, Rooming Houses, Boarding Houses, and Residential Hotels," Michael Mostoller undated (Box 18, Folder 10)
      - SRO Development and Management conferences 1985-92 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Massachusetts
      - General 1984-89, undated (Box 18, Folder 12)
      - "The Case for Preserving and Creating SRO Housing in Massachusetts," Citizens' Housing and Planning Association (CHAPA) 1990 (Box 18, Folder 13)
      - Executive Office of Communities and Development SRO Inventory 1990-91 (Box 18, Folder 14)
      - "The Preservation of Rooming Houses in Massachusetts," SRO Working Group 1986 (Box 18, Folder 15)
      - Report on the Beacon Chambers Hotel fire, Boston circa 1981 (Box 18, Folder 16)
      - SRO Moratorium bill 1989-90 (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - Springfield
      - General 1956-88 (Box 18, Folder 18)
        - Report 1985-86 (Box 18, Folder 19)
        - Research and notes 1984-85, undated (Box 18, Folder 20)
        - Contacts undated (Box 18, Folder 21)
      - Service Providers, Inc., SRO Project
        - General 1985-86, undated (Box 18, Folder 22)
        - Grant proposal to Massachusetts Executive Office of Communities and Development 1986 (Box 18, Folder 23)
        - Potential funding sources 1985, undated (Box 18, Folder 24)
        - Buildings - possibilities for SRO
          - General 1985-86, undated (Box 18, Folder 25)
          - Carlton Hotel 1986 (Box 18, Folder 26)
          - Hotel Charles 1988-94, undated (Box 18, Folder 27)
          - Tapley School 1989, undated (Box 18, Folder 28)
      - Rainville Hotel, 32 Byers St.
        - General 1990-2006, undated (Box 18, Folder 29)
        - Administration and management undated (Box 18, Folder 30)
        - Architects and contractors 1992-1994, undated (Box 18, Folder 31)
        - Board and meeting minutes 1991-2001, undated (Box 18, Folder 32-35)
        - The Community Builders 1991-94 (Box 18, Folder 36)
        - Financial 1988-94, undated (Box 18, Folder 37-40)
        - Legal 1992-94 (Box 18, Folder 41)
        - Market Feasibility Evaluation 1992 (Box 19, Folder 1)
        - National Register of Historic Places 1992 (Box 19, Folder 2)
        - Section 8 Moderate Rehabilitation Subsidies application 1992 (Box 19, Folder 3)
        - Social Services Plan and associated organizations 1992-94 (Box 19, Folder 4)
        - South Middlesex Non-Profit Housing Corp (SMOC) 1993-94 (Box 19, Folder 5)
        - Subsurface 21E Investigations 1992 (Box 19, Folder 6)